(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-19T17:04:32.877241",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Happy day to you!
今日は年に一度 特別な日
Today is a once-in-a-year special day,
君と一緒に 今お祝いをしよう
let's celebrate together right now.
ケーキの上の ローソク火をつけて
Light the candle on top of the cake,
「おめでとう」笑顔が溢れるよ
and say "Congratulations" with overflowing smiles.
生まれてきたこと それは偶然？奇跡？かもしれない
Being born into this world—coincidence? A miracle? Maybe.
でもせっかくなら 日々をもっと happy！ enjoy！
But since we're here, let's make every day more happy! enjoy!
さあ行こう！
Let's go!
happy！ enjoy！
happy! enjoy!
いつだってそう「僕なんて」さって
Whenever I'd say "someone like me,"
俯いてばかりのMayday
hanging my head in endless Mayday,
つまづいて泣いて
stumbling and crying,
「どうせ」って口癖が染み付いてさ
with "oh well" as my constant habit.
いつからかまた積もる焦り
Before I knew it, impatience piled up again,
でも胸の奥にある光
but the light deep in my chest
繋ぐ点と線の上
connects the dots and lines above.
踏み出すイメージの先へ
Heading beyond the image of stepping forward—
遠くたっていい
It's okay if it's far away.
ほら 虹をまたいで
Look, stepping across the rainbow,
さあ 心のままに音を奏でる
come on, let's play music straight from the heart!
逸る鼓動は今を刻む証だ
This racing heartbeat is proof that we carve out the present moment!
響け 僕らの想いを乗せて
Resound, carrying our feelings,
高く遠く 歌を紡いで
spinning songs high and far!
La la la
季節巡って 駆け抜けて
Seasons pass as we run through,
気づけば大人になってて
and before I knew it, I grew up.
幼い日の心は胸の奥くすぐってた
The feelings of my childhood still tickle deep in my heart.
怖いことも増えたけど
Even though things to fear have increased,
でも今だから見える世界
the world I can see now because of that—
僅さの中に確かに灯る光
a light that surely burns within the little things—
繋いでいこう
let's keep connecting them.
さあ 新しいステージへ
Now, onto a new stage,
心の中の音を聴かせて
let us hear the music in our hearts.
大袈裟だっていい
It's okay if it's over-the-top,
ありのままの自分で咲き誇れもっと
bloom proudly as your true self, even more!
いつでもずっと
Always and forever,
歌いながら日々を紡いで
spinning our days while singing.
俯いて泣いた日もあった
There were days I hung my head and cried,
だけど涙も力になる
but even tears become strength.
刻め HEART 鳴らせ BEAT
Carve it, HEART! Ring out, BEAT!
響け僕らのメロディ
Resound, our melody!
ねえ あの日の夢も 今の自分も 描く未来も
Hey, the dream of that day, my present self, the future I draw—
全て抱きしめるよ
I'll embrace them all.
さあ 旅を続けよう
Now, let's continue our journey,
どこまでもしずーっと手をつないで
holding hands forever and ever.
ほら 僕らの第一歩だ
Look, it's our first step!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
叶いたい未来へ
Toward the future I want to make true,
心の準備 OK？
is your heart ready?
さあ 一歩踏み出して いっせーの、せっ！
Now, take a step forward—one, two, three, go!
今日も楽しんでいこうしゃ
Let's enjoy today as well!
真っ白な羊に命が宿って
Life breathes into a pure white sheep,
目覚めたんだ この大きな世界で
and it awakens in this vast world.
何をしようか どこに行こうか
What shall we do? Where shall we go?
冒険は始まった
The adventure has begun!
ぐらついた足取りではおっかなびっくり
With wobbly steps, feeling timid and scared,
声を震わせて上手く泣けない
my voice trembles and I can't even cry properly.
そんな自分が嫌いじゃない
But I don't hate that side of me,
自信喪失気味でさ
though I'm feeling a bit lacking in confidence.
でも時間は進む 気持ちばかり焦る
Yet time moves on, and my feelings just rush ahead.
ゆっくりでいいから 泣いてちゃダメだよ
Slow down is fine, but crying won't do any good!
叶いたい未来へ
Toward the future I want to make true,
心の準備 OK？
is your heart ready?
さあ 一歩踏み出して ワンツーシー！
Now, take a step forward—one, two, three!
僕は君と出会って
Meeting you,
自信を取り戻して
I recovered my confidence,
ゆっくりと今確かに歩み出した
and slowly, surely, I took my first step today.
夢を見つけて いくつも抱きかかえて
Finding dreams, embracing so many of them,
君と話した 未来を掴みに行こう 一緒に隣歩いていこう
let's go seize the future we talked about together, walking side by side!
真っ白な羊に迷いはないさ
A pure white sheep has no hesitation;
走り出したら急には止まれない
once she starts running, she can't stop suddenly!
周りを巻き込む そんな羊に今なれる気がしたんだ
I felt like I could become a sheep right now who sweeps everyone along.
明日を迎えなくたっていいの？
Is it really okay not to welcome tomorrow?
朝も昼も夜も 半分こして食べ合って 夢みよう このまま一緒に夜に溶けて
Sharing mornings, afternoons, and nights, let's dream and melt into the night together!
君と出会って
Meeting you,
自信を取り戻して
I recovered my confidence,
泥まみれでも何度でも走り出した
and covered in mud, I started running over and over again!
夢を見つけて
Finding dreams...
Finding dreams,
いくつも抱きかかえて
holding so many in my arms,
君と話した
talking with you,
未来を掴みに行こう
let's go seize our future!
見たこともない
A world with scenery we've never seen before,
景色広がる世界へ連れて行くよ
I'll lead you to that expansive world.
一緒にずっと歩いていこう
Let's walk together forever.
同じ未来へ
Toward the same future.
いやあ、聞いてくれてありがとうございます！
Phew! Thank you so much for listening!
改めまして、こんばんは！ホロライブ4期生、角巻わためです！
Once again, good evening! I'm Watame Tsunomaki from Hololive 4th Gen!
なんと！3歳からホロライブデビューして、7歳になりました！いぇーい！
And what's more! I debuted in Hololive at 3 years old, and now I'm 7! Yay!
6月6日は羊の日でもあり、わためのお誕生日ということで、たくさんおめでとう、ありがとうございます！
June 6th is Sheep Day and also my birthday, so thank you so much for all the birthday wishes!
もっと欲しいな、もっともっと欲しいな、おめでとう！あ、もっともっと…ありがとう！
I want more, I want even more happy birthdays! Oh, even more... thank you!
コメント見えてんで、ありがとうございます！
I can see your comments, thank you!
いや1曲目はね、「Happy Days to You」という、わためオリジナル曲を歌わせていただきまして、
Well, for the first song, I sang my original song 'Happy Days to You'.
次に「夢見る羊」歌わせていただいたけど、どうだったかな？
And then I sang 'Yumemiru Hitsuji', but how was it?
どうだったかな？もうね、ドキドキ緊張してね、はあ、ちゃんと踊れてたかな、歌えてたかな。
How was it? You know, my heart was pounding with nervousness—phew, I wonder if I danced and sang properly.
でもこうやってスクショとか、みんながいっぱい撮ってくれて、で、Twitterにね、いつものね、このね、#角巻わため生誕祭2023というタグをつけて、
Even so, you all take lots of screenshots and post them on Twitter with the usual hashtag #角巻わため生誕祭2023,
いっぱい感想とかはね、ツイートしていただけますと、わためも後から見てそれが自信につながるので、ぜひバシバシと投稿して頂きたいなと思います。
if you tweet lots of your thoughts, I'll read them later and it builds my confidence, so I'd love for you to post tons of them!
なんと今日は…ま、まだまだ歌ったり踊ったりするんだけど、重大告知もありますので、ぜひ楽しんでいて頂きたいなと思います！一緒に楽しんでいきましょう！
And today... well, I'll still be singing and dancing more, but there are major announcements coming up too, so I hope you'll enjoy it! Let's enjoy it together!
では、真ん中のステージに次人は移動したいと思います！行くぞー！
Now, I'd like to move to the center stage next! Let's go!
人魚姫
[Title: Ningyohime / Little Mermaid]
深い眠りの中 月夜の風で
In a deep slumber, in the moonlight wind,
小さな泡になって消えてしまわないように
so that I don't turn into small bubbles and vanish,
いっそ私があの人魚姫なら
if only I were that Little Mermaid,
泡になって消えてしまえるのにね
I could turn into bubbles and disappear...
傷ついた顔を見せないために
To keep from showing my wounded face,
偽りの笑顔を振りまいていたけれど
I kept flashing a feigned smile,
もっと私があの嘘をつければいいのに
if only I could tell lies a bit better,
信じたかったんだ
I wanted to believe
あなたがオジ様だって どれだけ愛してたっけ
that you were my prince... Just how much I loved you.
あなたとの悲しみの海で 溺れそうな思いも今は
In the ocean of sorrow with you, the feelings of almost drowning—now,
私はおとぎ話の 人魚姫みたいだ
I'm like the Little Mermaid from a fairy tale.
どれくらいどかけて 戦う日まで
How long will it take until the day we fight?
あとどのくらい
Just how much longer?
準備はできている もう迷わない 後悔はしない 止まる言葉は
I'm ready. I won't hesitate anymore, I won't regret anything...
昨今迷子でぐだぐだぐだ
Lately, I'm lost and all over the place.
もうハイ or ロー ガチャでぐちゃぐちゃ更新
High or low, gacha results keep updating the mess.
合唱 ネガ and ポジる らららら
Chanting negative and positive, lalalalala.
まあ一度歌うわなんてこったいな感
Well, singing once gives this what-the-heck feeling.
美々美なビリビリ
Beautiful, beautiful static electricity.
昨今やるだけやるしかない
Lately, all I can do is just do it.
もうちっちゃいことで凹んでらんない
Can't stay down over little things anymore.
圧倒するまで育つんだ系
Growing until I overwhelm everyone.
さあ心配要らずのジェットコースター
Now, a rollercoaster with nothing to worry about!
いけいけチャンス
Go, go, chance!
研ぎ澄ました希望でおめかし
Dressing up with sharpened hope.
さーこさこハッピーでいっぱい
Filled to the brim with happy vibes.
いけいけチャンス
Go, go, chance!
炊き込んだ願いが香り立つ
The cooked wish wafts its aroma.
今僕になるんだ
Now, I'm becoming myself.
僕しかできないこと認めてほしいの
I want you to acknowledge only I can do this.
「どうせ」とか思ってらんないわ
Can't be thinking "no way" anymore.
だってー妄想ばこん！切り刻んでいこう
Come on, delusions, bam! Let's chop 'em up.
まだ一等賞まで放電がありそう
Still looks like I've got energy until first prize.
当選しちゃうかは挑戦次第
Whether I win depends on the challenge.
オーケーやるかやれないかだ
Okay, it's do or die.
「はぁ めんどいっぽい」
"Ugh, seems like a pain."
「これで エンドっぽい」
"Feels like this is the end."
叩き壊した弱音がちょービタイ
Smashing my weak words is super vital.
夢が叶っちゃって甘くなれ
Dreams came true, so go soft.
黙れ不完全はノーノーノーグッバイ
Shut up, imperfection is a no-no-no goodbye.
美々美なビリビリ
Beautiful, beautiful static electricity.
昨今やるのことやるだけバッド
Lately, just doing what I do is bad.
もう涙腺アミダ全泣きが確定
Tear ducts decided, total crying is guaranteed.
同情求めてはわわわわ
Begging for sympathy, wawawa.
ねぇちゃんと言い締めれてえっえっ…
Hey, embracing properly, eh, eh...
にげにげチャンス
Runaway, runaway chance!
顔出した絶望で
With despair showing its face,
ごまかし乗る歌詞ハッピーが足んない
Covering it up, happy lyrics aren't enough.
にげにげチャンス
Runaway, runaway chance!
あたしを愛せない
I can't love myself.
比べたら比べただけ負け犬
The more I compare, the more of a loser I am.
ありなし選べちゃうけど弱気になるかも
I can choose yes or no, but I might get timid.
「どうせ無理」と思っていじけちゃうわ
Thinking "no way" makes me sulk.
だってー有言だもん！叶わないもん
Because I spoke my words! But they won't come true.
また一等賞指くわえて見ているの
Staring at first prize with my thumb in my mouth.
あたしじゃない誰かだったの
It was someone else, not me.
ノーノー誰か倒れてよ
No, no, someone else fall down.
せーので段違いの未来
On three, a different level of future.
いやいや無理だってば
No way, no way, that's impossible.
前進もっとハイになって
Move forward, get even higher.
うんきびしー
Yeah, that's rough.
贅沢夢浸りていたい
I want to soak in luxurious dreams.
息ができないー
I can't breathe!
ローさん黙ってね？
Low-san, be quiet, okay?
わいわいぜーんぶ無駄、そうに決まんないじゃん
Yay, yay, it's all useless, it's not decided like that.
は？ハイさん圧が強すぎーブレイクブレイクアクセル！
Huh? High-san, the pressure is too strong—break, break, accelerator!
噛み合わないね笑えるくらいならこのままいくしかないか
We don't click, if it's funny enough, we just gotta keep going.
役割分担それがいいかしら
Division of labor, I wonder if that's good.
大丈夫！
It'll be fine!
無理無理重ねて
Piling up impossibilities,
僕しか会えない子と仲良くしてるの
I'm getting along with the one only I can meet.
どうせならかまってみちまい満ちますか
Since we're at it, should we pay attention and fill up?
だってー妄想ばこん！切り刻んでいこう
Come on, delusions, bam! Let's chop 'em up.
まだ一等賞指くわえて見ても
Even if I stare at first prize with my thumb in my mouth,
誰かじゃない僕がいいんだよ
I want it to be me, not someone else.
そんなに僕らは無敵じゃない
We're not that invincible.
夢中になれたんならそれでいいのかい
If we could get lost in something, is that good enough?
宇宙の角が見つかるまで世界を求めている
Seeking the world until we find the corner of the universe.
コンクリートが溶けるような暑さの中
In a heat that melts concrete,
不純な水は君も持っている
You also carry impure water.
誰も飲まないけれども口ゆすぐには慣れたなもう慣れた
No one drinks it, but we're used to rinsing our mouths with it now.
日が沈む中
As the sun sets,
大人になった僕らが見る夢はまだ甘いか
Are the dreams we see as adults still sweet?
人知れず潜った僕の深海にはまだあった
In the deep sea I dove into secretly, it was still there.
溺れてしまうくらいに深くて人を知るには暗い
So deep I'd drown, too dark to understand people.
一筋の光君と身を寄せているくじらみたいに
A single ray of light, clinging to you like a whale.
呼吸の跡が残るくらいの寒さが身を貫く前には
Before the cold that leaves a mark from our breath pierces us,
急げ暖をとって怒りの火種木をくべお湯を沸かし人を癒すか
Hurry and take warmth, fuel the fire, boil water to heal people.
孤独になった僕らが見る夢はまだ淡いが
The dreams we see in our loneliness are still faint, but
人知れず作った秘密の基地にはあった
In the secret base I built without anyone knowing, it was there.
狂えるほどに愛おしくて君を想うにはやさしい
Love so intense it drives me crazy, gentle when thinking of you.
一つ屋根の下で笑い合えるそんな日々と
Those days when we could laugh together under the same roof.
くじらだったらなくじらだったらなくじらだったらな
If only we were whales, if only we were whales...
君を信じるだけでよかった
Just believing in you would have been enough.
くじらだったらなくじらだったらなくじらだったらな
If only we were whales, if only we were whales...
家族を守るだけでよかった
Just protecting our family would have been enough.
目を閉じたまま
With our eyes closed,
大人になった僕らが見る夢はまだ甘いか
Are the dreams we see as adults still sweet?
人知れず潜った僕的心臓にはまだあった
In the heart I dove into secretly, it was still there.
溺れてしまうくらいに深くて人を知るには暗い
So deep I'd drown, too dark to understand people.
一筋の光君と身を寄せているくじらみたいに
A single ray of light, clinging to you like a whale.
くじらだったらな
If only we were whales...
いつだって そう 「僕 なんて 」 って
Always, yeah, saying "someone like me..."
うなだれてばかりの may day
On this gloomy may day,
つまづいて 泣いて 「どうせ」 って 口癖が染み付いてさ
stumbling and crying, "oh well" becoming my catchphrase.
いつからか まだ 積もる 焦り
Frustration has piled up since when?
でも 胸 の 奥 に ある 光
Yet there's a light deep inside my chest,
繋ぐ 点 と 線 の 上
upon the connecting dots and lines.
踏み出す イメージ の 先 へ 遠くたっていい
Stepping out beyond the image, it's okay if it's far away.
ほら 虹 を またいで
Look, straddling the rainbow,
さあ 心 の まま に 音 を 奏でる
come play the music straight from your heart.
逸る 鼓動 は 今 を 刻む 証 だ
This racing heartbeat is proof of marking the present.
響け 僕ら の 想い を 乗せ て
Resonate, carrying our feelings,
高く 遠く 歌 を 紡い で
weaving songs high and far.
la la la
季節 巡っ て 駆け抜け て き て
Seasons rotated, running through them,
気付け ば 大人 に なっ て て
before I knew it, I became an adult.
幼い 日 の 心 は 胸 の 奥 くすぶっ て た
My childish heart was smoldering deep inside my chest.
怖い こと も 増え た けれど
Things I'm afraid of increased too,
でも 今 だから 見える 世界
yet this world is visible because it's now.
僅か さ の 中 に 確実 に 灯る 光
A light that surely glows within the smallness—
繋い で いこ う
let's keep connecting it.
さあ 新しい ステージ へ
Now, to a new stage,
心 の 中 の 音 を 聴か せ て
let us hear the sound inside your heart.
大袈裟 で たって いい
It's okay to make a big deal out of it;
ありのまま の 自分 で
as your true self,
咲き誇れ もっと
bloom even more proudly,
いつまでも ずっと
forever and ever.
歌い ながら 日々 を 紡い で
Weaving through days while singing,
劣い て 泣い た 日 も あっ た
there were days I cried while feeling inferior,
けど 涙 も 力 に なる
but tears also turn into strength.
刻め heart
Carve into your heart,
鳴らせ beat
ring out the beat.
誰もいない 誰も知らない
No one is here, no one knows,
名前のない今をかけていくの
running through an unnamed present.
あの海を消えても伸ばして
Even if that sea disappears, reach out,
誰もいない 誰も知らない
no one is here, no one knows.
君を知りたい これ以上になれない臆病の良さも
I want to know you, even the cowardice of not going further,
誰もいない 誰も知らない
no one is here, no one knows.
名前のない今をかけていくの
running through an unnamed present.
あの海を消えても伸ばして
Even if that sea disappears, reach out,
誰もいない 誰も知らない
no one is here, no one knows.
君を知りたい これ以上になれない臆病の良さも
I want to know you, even the cowardice of not going further,
臍の緒がプチっと切れたその時
The moment the umbilical cord snapped,
世界からはぐれてしまったみたいだ
it felt like I got separated from the world.
目に映る景色が悲しく笑うなら
If the scenery reflecting in my eyes smiles sadly,
恐れず瞼を閉じてごらん
try closing your eyelids without fear.
さあ見知らぬこちらへどうぞことのなる方へさ
Now come on over here to the unknown, towards the changing ways,
踵を打ち鳴らせどうぞ心の踊る方へさ
stamp your heels, towards where your heart dances,
真新しい扉に飛び乗って
jump onto a brand new door,
殺伐とした世界乗りこなして
and ride through this cutthroat world.
誰もいない 誰も知らない
No one is here, no one knows,
やまない愛を知りたいと願うの
wishing to know an endless love.
まちがい 時を越えて さかさま夜まで
Mistakes, transcending time, until the upside-down night,
誰もいない 誰も知らない
no one is here, no one knows.
君を知りたい 何ひとつ見逃さぬように
I want to know you, so I don't miss a single thing.
時は誰も待ってくれないの
Time waits for no one.
残酷な運命が 逆らえぬ宿命が
Crucial fate, inescapable destiny,
考える間もなく押し寄せるなら
if it comes rushing in without giving time to think,
前髪見えなくたって
even if my bangs obscure my view,
君を信じてみたいの
I want to try believing in you.
恐れずに一歩踏み出したら...
If I take a step forward without fear...
ひとひらの 夢々に焦がれて
Longing for a single petal of a dream,
まっすぐで 強がったキミが居る
you stand straight, putting on a brave face.
物語る背中 美しすぎて 危うげで 少し心配
Your back tells a story, too beautiful and fragile.
時には陽の射さぬ 道を歩いていても
Even when walking down a path where the sun doesn't shine,
決してうつむかないよう 顔を上げて
never look down, raise your face.
会いたくなったら 思い出して 僕はすっとキミのカゲボウシ
If you want to see me, remember me, I am always your shadow.
駆け抜けて 心のままに どこまでも寄り添うから
Run through, following your heart, staying close no matter where.
嬉しくなったよ キミが居るから 僕の未来も微笑みばかり
I'm happy because you're here, my future is full of smiles.
ありがとう この胸の中 優しさでいっぱいだよ
Thank you, my heart is full of tenderness.
聞いてくれて ありがとうございました。
Thank you so much for listening.
どうだったかな。
How was it?
人魚姫、クジラ、ゆうと 歌わせていただいたんですが、
I sang 'Little Mermaid', 'Whale', and 'Yuu',
これには実は テーマがありまして、
but actually, there is a theme to this.
何のテーマでしょう？
What could the theme be?
人魚姫、クジラ、ゆう。
Little Mermaid, Whale, Yuu.
そして、このステージを 見てもらったら分かるかなと思うんですが、
And if you look at this stage, you might understand.
え、テーマは海の曲を 歌わせていただきました。
The theme was, I sang songs about the sea.
いや、見て、このステージ、すごいよね！
Man, look at this stage, it's amazing!
スタッフさんたちが頑張って 制作してくださってまして、
The staff worked so hard to produce this,
このスクリーンもね、全面にこれ繋がってて、すごいね！
and this screen is connected all across, amazing!
いや、また後でね、見返してほしいんだけど、この全面スクリーンで、
I want you to rewatch it later with this full screen,
この後ろで泳いでるクジラかな？イルカかな？
swimming behind me is a whale? A dolphin?
なんだろね、魚たちがね、泳いでいたり、
I wonder what it is, fish swimming around,
あとはヒトデとか、ホタテかな？とかね、置いて下さって、
starfish, scallops? They placed all these things,
ここは深海、海のなかを 表現しております。
expressing the deep sea.
みんな息やつづいているかな？海のなかでライブやってるけど大丈夫かな？
Is everyone's breath holding up? Doing a live show inside the ocean, is it okay?
実はこのテーマの「海」というのも、重大告知にちょっと関係してくると言いますか、
Actually, this theme of "ocean" relates to a major announcement.
なんだろ、気になるね！
I wonder what it is!
この後も楽しんで いただけたらなと思います。
I hope you'll enjoy the rest of it.
ここからは、わための 大好きなポルノグラフィティさんの歌を歌っていこうと思います。
Now I'll sing a song by Porno Graffitti, whom I love.
私は私と はぐれるわけにはいかないから
I can't be separated from myself, so
いつかまた 逢いましょう その日まで サヨナラ恋心よ
someday we'll meet again, until that day, goodbye, my love.
嘘をつくくらいなら 何も話してくれなくていい
If you're going to lie, you don't have to explain anything.
あなたは去っていくの それだけは分かっているから
You're going away, I know that much.
見つめ合った私は 可愛い女じゃなかったね
I wasn't the prettiest girl you've ever seen as we stared at each other.
せめて最後は 笑顔で飾らせて
At least let me end with a smile.
涙が悲しみを溶かして 溢れるものだとしたら
If tears melt away sorrow and overflow,
その雫ももう一度 飲み干してしまいたい
I want to drink up every drop of them once more.
凛とした痛み 胸に留まり続ける限り
As long as this dignified pain stays in my heart,
あなたを忘れずに いられるでしょう
I'll never forget you.
許してね 恋心よ 甘い夢は波にさらわれたの
Forgive me, my love, sweet dreams were swept away by waves.
いつかまた 逢いましょう その日まで サヨナラ恋心よ
Someday we'll meet again, until that day, goodbye, my love.
時を重ねるごとに ひとつずつあなたを知っていって
With each passing moment, I get to know you one by one.
さらに時間を重ねて ひとつずつ分からなくなって
And as time goes by, one by one I lose track of you.
愛が消えていくのを 夕日にたててみたりして
I compare the fading of love to the setting sun.
そこに確実に残る サウダージ
The saudade that surely remains there.
繰り返しよくある話 出会いと別れ 泣くも笑うも 好きも嫌いも
It's the same old story: encounters, partings, tears, and smiles.
許してね 恋心よ 甘い夢は波にさらわれたの
Forgive me, my love, sweet dreams were swept away by waves.
いつかまた 逢いましょう その日まで サヨナラ恋心よ
Someday we'll meet again, until that day, goodbye, my love.
あなたの傍では 永遠を確実に感じたから
I've felt eternity by your side.
夜空を焦がして 私は生きよう 恋心よ
Scorching the night sky, I'll live my life, my love.
諦めて 恋心よ
Give up, my aching heart,
青い期待は 私を切り裂くだけ
naive expectations only tear me apart.
あのひとに 伝えて
Tell that person...
「寂しい」「大丈夫」「寂しい」
"Are you lonely?" "Are you okay?" "Are you lonely?"
繰り返し 返される
Repeatedly echoing back,
よくある 話し
a common story of desires.
出逢いとは 別れ
Meetings mean partings,
ぬくもりも 嫌いも
warmth and hatred alike.
諦めて 恋心よ
Give up, my aching heart,
甘い夢は 波にさらわれたの
sweet dreams were swept away by the waves.
いつか また逢いましょう
Let's meet again someday,
その日まで さよなら
goodbye until that day.
恋心よ あなたのそばでは
My aching heart, by your side,
永遠を 確かに感じだから
I truly felt eternity, so
夜空を焦がして 私は生きたわ
I scorched the night sky and lived.
恋心よ
My aching heart...
Babe, babe, tell me now
ロンリー・チャイルド ロンリー・チャイルド
lonely child, lonely child...
ロンリー・チャイルド ロンリー・チャイルド ロンリー・チャイルド
Lonely child, lonely child, lonely child...
Zombies are crying out 荒みきった crazy town
Zombies are crying out in a warped crazy town,
現実という名の bullet に 撃ち抜かれた
shot down by a bullet called reality.
Zombies are crying out 蠢いている my head
Zombies are crying out, writhing in my head—
何を探し彷徨っているのか
what is it I'm searching and wandering for?
赤く爛れた繊細な器官
A delicately inflamed, red organ,
感情を喪失した焦点の合わない目
empty eyes that have lost all emotion.
この街をべっとりと覆い尽くす 大気汚染
Air pollution tightly blanketing this town...
hands come out underground
安らぎは与えられない
peace can never be granted.
Zombies are standing out
渇望している 安息
craving sweet rest.
脳裏に残っている朧げな記憶がまた
The hazy memories lingering in my mind...
Zombies are standing out 蘇るは glory days
Zombies are standing out, reviving glory days.
ここじゃ誰も眠ってはならぬ
No one is allowed to sleep here.
醜態を晒し続ける
Continuing to expose our ugliness.
Zombies are crying out 荒みきった crazy town
Zombies are crying out in a warped crazy town,
現実という名の bullet に 撃ち抜かれた
shot down by a bullet called reality.
Zombies are crying out 蠢いている my head
Zombies are crying out, writhing in my head—
何を探し彷徨っているのか
what is it I'm searching and wandering for?
i still pray to revive
躯を焼き灰になって
burning my body to ash.
Zombies are crying out
荒みきった Crazy town
a desolate, crazy town,
現実という名の Bullet に撃ち抜かれた
shot through by a bullet called reality.
Zombies are crying out
怯えている My head
my terrified head.
何を探し彷徨っているの?
What am I wandering around searching for?
光がその躯を焼き 灰になって いつか
May light scorch that body to ash, so that one day
神の祝福を受けられるように
I may receive God's blessing.
I still pray to revive
清らかな水…
pure water...
清らかな水も枯れ 焼け付くこの喉に
Even pure water dries up in this scorching throat.
声が枯れる本当に叫んでいるだけど
My voice is hoarse, but I am truly screaming.
Zombies are standing out
地平なき闇では
in a darkness without a horizon.
狂い死して生きる永久の
Dying of madness, living an eternal...
天生 立ち上がれ Level up
Reincarnation, stand up and level up!
Zombies remember me
夢見た明日を…
tomorrow that I dreamed of...
静けさがしみ込むように息を止めた午前5時
As if silence sinking in, I stopped breathing at 5 a.m.
非常階段で爪を噛む 明日はどっちだ?
Biting my nails on the fire escape, which way is tomorrow?
THE DAY HAS COME
決して明けない夜も
Even nights that never break,
降り続けてやみない雨も
and rains that fall without end,
このろくでもない世界にはあるんだよ
exist in this good-for-nothing world.
少しも変ではないのさ 窓ろみに足を奪われてる
It's not strange at all, having your feet caught by drowsiness.
あなたを責めているわけじゃないんだよ
I'm not blaming you for it.
独り愚痴に遊ぶ
Playing with lonely complaints,
そこで思い描いたことまで恥ずるのかい?
are you even ashamed of what you pictured there?
絡み合う 迷宮 迷宮
Entangling labyrinth, labyrinth,
それでも行くというのか?
do you still say you'll go?
小さき旅人が奏でる 始まりの鐘の音
The sound of the starting bell played by a small traveler.
行く手も DON'T KNOW DON'T KNOW
Not even knowing the path ahead, DON'T KNOW DON'T KNOW,
本当は怖いんじゃないのか?
aren't you actually scared?
踏み出すその一歩一歩が変えていけるさ THE DAY HAS COME
Every step you take forward can change things, THE DAY HAS COME.
その目で見たものだけ信じていたいけれど
I want to believe only in what I saw with my own eyes, but
影に怯えては 悪い予感が本当に化ける CRY ON CRY ON
trembling in shadows, bad premonitions turn into reality, CRY ON CRY ON.
果てしない REAL SURVIVOR 足を引っ張り合う
Endless REAL SURVIVOR, dragging each other down,
生き残った者が勝者で "FAIR" などは幻想
the survivor is the victor, and "FAIR" is just an illusion.
忍び寄る SECRET HUNTER 語るのは天下国家
Creeping SECRET HUNTER, speaking of the nation and state.
絡み合う 迷宮 迷宮 それでも行くというのか?
Entangling labyrinth, labyrinth, do you still say you'll go?
小さき旅人が奏でる 始まりの鐘の音
The sound of the starting bell played by a small traveler.
行く手も DON'T KNOW DON'T KNOW 本当は怖いんじゃないのか?
Not even knowing the path ahead, DON'T KNOW DON'T KNOW, aren't you actually scared?
踏み出すその一歩一歩が変えていけるさ THE DAY HAS COME
Every step you take forward can change things, THE DAY HAS COME.
THE DAY HAS COME
その目で見たものだけ信じていたいけれど影に怯えては
I want to believe only in what I saw with my own eyes, but trembling in shadows,
悪い予感が本当に化ける CRY ON CRY ON
bad premonitions turn into reality, CRY ON CRY ON.
果てしないリアルサバイバル
A never-ending real survival,
足を引っ張り合う
pulling each other down.
生き残った者が勝者で
The survivor is the winner,
公平などは幻想
and fairness is an illusion.
忍び寄る
Creeping up,
シュプレヒコール
shouting slogans—
語るのは天国か地獄か
do they speak of heaven or hell?
一畳の階段で爪を研ぐ
Sharpening claws on a tiny stair,
浅い眠りを血塗られたぜ
blood-staining our shallow sleep.
果てしないリアルサバイバル
A never-ending real survival,
塗りつぶせ
paint it over!
誰より高く手を伸ばせ
Reach higher than anyone else,
朝も夜も血塗られたぜ
blood-staining both morning and night.
聞いてくれて、ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for listening.
配信のタイトルにも、させていただきました。
I even used it for the stream's title.
「ザ・デイ」でした。
It was "THE DAY."
これまで、ハッピー・デイ・トゥ・ユー
Up until now, "Happy day to you,"
ま、お祝いの曲から
well, starting from the celebration song,
夢見る羊、夢を叶える準備はいいですか？
"Dreaming Sheep, are you ready for your dreams?"
オッケー、という曲。
A song called "Okay."
そして、海の曲、ステージ、このステージ
And then the ocean song, the stage, this stage—
からの、ポルノグラフィティさんの曲、これは一体どういうことなのか分かるかな？
followed by Porno Graffitti's song. Do you know what this is all about?
なんだろうな？分かるかな？
I wonder what it is? Do you know?
え、今からめちゃくちゃすごい重大告知をしようかと思うんです。
Um, I'm thinking of making a super huge, major announcement right now.
これまでの曲もね、今から告知する内容に、ま、絡んだ、ちなんだテーマとなっているんですが
The previous songs are also themed around and connected to the announcement I'm about to make, but...
この度、わための夢が一つ叶いました！
This time, one of Watame's dreams has come true!
なんと、ポルノグラフィティのお二人に新曲を制作していただきましたー！
Amazingly, the two of them from Porno Graffitti wrote a brand new song for me!
いや、すごいことだよ、これは！
Man, this is such an incredible thing!
どうすごいかというと、あの岡野昭仁さんと新堂晴一さんが二人揃って楽曲を提供するということは、初めてなんだよね！
How amazing is it? Well, for Akihito Okano and Haruichi Shindo to both provide a song together for the first time ever!
すごくない？
Isn't that amazing?
これはすごいことだと思うんだけど、どうかな？
I think this is an incredible thing, but what do you think?
そして、なんと今日は、お二人からメッセージもいただいておりますので、読ませていただきたいと思います。
And what's more, today we've also received messages from the two of them, so I'd like to read them out.
では、読みます。
Now, I'll read them.
角巻さんの明るく、愛されるキャラクターをイメージして曲を作りました。
"I created this song imagining Tsunomaki-san's bright, lovable character."
ファンの皆さんと一緒に歌い、盛り上がってくれたら嬉しいです。
"I'd be happy if you could sing along with the fans and get hyped."
そして、お誕生日おめでとうございます！ 岡野昭仁
"And happy birthday! — Okano Akihito"
キスツ、ありがとうございます！ ディスパッチャーズも応援しております！
Kitz, thank you so much! Dispatchers are supporting you too!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
"Happy birthday!"
この曲をどんな風に表現してもらえるか楽しみにしています。 新藤晴一
"I'm looking forward to how you'll express this song. — Shindo Haruichi"
晴一さん、晴一さんもありがとうございます！ ミュージカル応援しております！
Haruichi-san, thank you to Haruichi-san as well! I'm supporting your musical!
嬉しいね。 このね、文字数の差とかもね
I'm so happy. And you know, the difference in word count—
ポルノグラフィティのね、「ラバアップ」っていうファンクラブに入ってる人は分かると思うんだけど
For those in Porno Graffitti's fan club "Love Up!", you'd probably understand—
大体ね、岡野昭仁さんの方が、あの文字数がね、文字のほうが多くて、で、晴一さんの方が少ないみたいなのがあるよね（笑）
generally, Okano Akihito-san's has more text/characters, and Haruichi-san's is fewer, right? (Laughs)
ラバパ、知恵袋でした（笑）
Love-Up Wisdom! (Laughs)
いや、嬉しい！ みんなのおかげで、こうしてまた一つ夢を叶えることができました。
Man, I'm so happy! Thanks to everyone, I was able to make yet another dream come true.
そして、曲名が「ヴィンズ」という曲名になっております。
And the song title is "Vinz."
まあちょっと曲をね、聴いていただいたなら分かるかなと思うんですけど
Today, I'd like to talk a bit about...
まあちょっと海にちなんだと言おうか
Well, my ocean journey, so to speak.
まあちょっと頑張ろうかなと思えるような、そんな爽やかでちょっと頑張ってみよう、元気になれるような
I want to do my best, and feel refreshed and energized, like...
またみんなと一緒に頑張ろうねみたいな、なんかそんな曲になっておりますので、ぜひ聴いて欲しいなと思います。
Let's all do our best together! I wanted to make a song just like that, so I hope you'll listen to it.
心を込めて歌います。それでは聴いてください。「Fins」
Putting my heart into it, I will sing. Please listen. Fins!
Every emotions has a fin
Every emotion has a fin,
It takes me to beautiful places
心 泳ぐ 感情たちは
The emotions swimming in my heart
まるで銀の渦の翅
Are like the silver fins of a vortex.
未だ形 定まらずに
Still without a defined shape,
水に跳ねる光の粒を追って
Chasing the particles of light dancing on the water.
それじゃ気まま過ぎると僕を責めるかい?
"If you're too carefree, are you blaming me?"
まるで予測不能 I don't know where to go?
Like unpredictable... I don't know where to go?
いつかは大きなソウルになるかな
Someday it will become a huge soul,
僕という輪郭を強く強く描くの
Strongly, strongly sketching the outline of who I am.
水面を飛び出し 翻してみせる
Leaping out of the water, making it flutter and show,
豪快な水飛沫
Splashing water dramatically,
今日の涙と共に空高くへ
Together with today's tears, up into the high sky.
いつも迷う感情たちが
The emotions that always wander
隠している意図をただ聞き取って
Just listening closely to the hidden intentions,
それが導く先が理想と違っても
Even if where they lead is different from the ideal,
遠く彼方であるならいい
As long as it's far away, that's fine.
巨大なハリケーン 不穏な未来は
A huge hurricane, an ominous future,
ギラついた目で睨む 怯えながらそれでも
Glaring with sharp eyes, even while trembling,
そいつとダンスを踊るということさ
Even so, dancing with that person
簡単じゃないけれど
It's not easy, but
手を差し出し優雅に誘うマナー
Reaching out a hand and gracefully inviting them—
生きてく理由に思いを巡らせ
Pondering the reason for living,
生まれたからと断言してみる
I'll assert that I was born for a reason.
それは深い海流のようなフィロソフィ
That is a philosophy like a deep ocean current,
僕は漂流してるばかりじゃないんだ
I'm not just drifting around.
Every emotions has a fin
Every emotion has a fin,
It takes me to beautiful places
いつかは大きなソウルになるかな
Someday it will become a huge soul,
僕という輪郭を強く強く描くの
Strongly, strongly sketching the outline of who I am.
水面を飛び出し 翻してみせる
Leaping out of the water, making it flutter and show,
豪快な水飛沫
Splashing water dramatically,
今日の涙と共に空高くへ
Together with today's tears, up into the high sky.
いつか みんなで
Someday, all together,
この曲をどうかんて歌いましょう
Let's sing this song together!
みんなのおかげで、また一つ夢を叶えることができました。
Thanks to everyone, we were able to make another dream come true.
みんな見てくれて、これからもよろしくね！
Thank you all for watching, and I look forward to your continued support!
だいぶ見てくれて、ありがとうございました。
Thank you so much for watching the premiere!
「Fins」どうだったでしょうか。
How did you like "Fins"?
デビュー当時からずっと尊敬してる、応援してるアーティストさんと言えば、
I've always said that ever since my debut, my most respected and supported artists
ポルノグラフィティさんだと言い続けていたので、
have been Porno Graffitti,
そのお二人から楽曲提供をしていただけたこと、今でも本当に夢のように感じます。
so having the two of them provide a song for me still feels like an absolute dream.
でもこのお知らせをみんなに届けることができて、本当に心から嬉しく思います。
But being able to share this announcement with everyone makes me truly and sincerely happy.
そんな角巻わため新オリジナル曲「Fins」がこのあと24時から各種音楽配信サービスにて配信開始となります。
My brand-new original song "Fins" will begin streaming on various music services starting at midnight tonight!
そして22時このあと10時からは、「Fins」のムービーがわためチャンネルにて投稿されますので、ぜひ見てください。
And starting at 10:00 PM tonight, the "Fins" movie will be posted on the Watame Channel, so please be sure to check it out.
そして角巻わため誕生日記念グッズが今年も出ます！
And Tsunomaki Watame's birthday commemorative goods are coming out this year too!
アクリルジオラスタンド、わためいと手袋、ステッカー、わためいとプロフィールカードドドの4種類になっております。
There are four items: an acrylic diorama stand, Watamates gloves, stickers, and Watamates profile cards.
グッズのフルセットをご購入いただいた方には、特典ボイスとポストカードがついてきます。
Those who purchase the full set of goods will receive a bonus voice track and a postcard.
今回も数量限定なしで、直筆サイン＆メッセージを書かせていただきますので、よろしくお願いします！
This time as well, there's no quantity limit, and I will write a handwritten signature and message on them, so I'm counting on your support!
ふーみママ描き下ろしのアクリルジオラスタンドはライブをテーマにしていて、
The acrylic diorama stand illustrated by Fuumi mama has a live concert theme,
わためいとバンドなど取り外しが可能なものもありますので、配置をお好みにいれかえることができたりします。
and since items like the Watamates band are removable, you can rearrange the placement however you like.
さらに、わためいと手袋！
Furthermore, the Watamates gloves!
こちらのグッズ、届くのがまた寒くなってきた頃になるかなと思うので、あったかモコモコグッズをご用意しました。
Since these goods will arrive when it starts getting cold again, I prepared warm and fluffy goods.
表は羊のような白色、内側はピンク。
The outside is sheep-like white, and the inside is pink.
今回はオーラわためいとのタグがついています。
This time, it features an Aura Watamates tag.
そしてステッカー！
And the stickers!
こちらはわため将軍やわためおじなど4種類のわため＋わためいとのシールになっております。
These are stickers featuring four types of Watamates plus Watame, like General Watame and Uncle Watame.
いつでも視界に入るようにパソコンや好きなところに貼ってほしいなと思います。
I'd love for you to stick them on your PC or somewhere you can always see them.
そしてそして、わためいとプロフィールカードドド！
And last but not least, the Watamates profile cards!
自分の名前や趣味などが書き込めるようになっているので、写真を撮ってSNSに投稿するなりイベントとかでわためいと同士でカード交換をしても楽しいかもと思って作らせていただきました。自由に使ってください。
Since you can write in your name and hobbies, I made these thinking it would be fun to take pictures and post them on SNS or exchange cards with other Watamates at events. Please use them freely!
この4点のグッズをセットでごご購入いただいた方には、取り下ろし特典ボイスとわためいの直筆サイン＆メッセージ入りポストカードがついてきます！
Those who purchase these four items as a set will receive a newly recorded bonus voice and a postcard with Watame's handwritten signature and message!
枚数制限なんとございませんので、遠慮なくたくさんゲットしてほしいなと思います。
There is no limit on the quantity, so I hope you'll get plenty of them without hesitation!
それぞれ単品販売もありますので、いいなと思うものがあったら後悔しないようにぜひ手に入れてください！
There are also individual sales for each, so if there's something you like, please make sure to get it so you don't regret it!
最後に、このあと22時15分からメンバーシップ限定アンコールライブを3Dで行いますので、
Lastly, starting at 10:15 PM tonight, I'll be holding a membership-only encore live in 3D,
まだまだ音楽を一緒に楽しみたいぜ！まだまだいけるぜ！という方はぜひメンバーシップに入ってちょっとおまちいただければと思います。
so if you're thinking, "I want to keep enjoying music together!" or "I'm ready for more!", I hope you'll join the membership and wait just a bit.
ではわためは準備をしてきますので、「Fins」のムービーを見て、グッズを買って待っててくださーい！
Well then, Watame is going to go get ready, so please watch the "Fins" movie, buy the goods, and wait for me!
それでは本当にみんないつもありがとう！
Thank you all so much, as always!
過ごしてきたたくさんの日々
The countless days we've spent together,
歩いてきた果てしない道
the endless road we've walked along...
ユメの景色たどり着くため
To arrive right where our dreams reside,
物語はまだ続いている
the story continues on.
きっとボクは自分自身じゃ輝けない
Surely, I cannot shine all on my own,
それはまるで夜空の月のように…
just like the moon in the night sky...
つまずいても傷付いても此処からまた始めよう
No matter how clumsy or wounded we are, let's start over from here.
不器用でも小さくても詩を歌い続けよう
Clumsily, however small, let's keep on singing our poem.
きっとほら届くから
I know it will surely reach you.
響け 響け
Resound, resound!
出会いの日曜日は祝いの詩を
A song of celebration for the day we met,
別れの日時は旅立ちの詩を
a song of departure for the day we part.
キミのためにトクベツな詩を紡ぎだそう
We'll weave a special poem just for you.
さあ 響け
Now, resound!
キミだけのメロディ
Your very own melody.
ララララ…
La la la...
きっとキミもひとりでは輝けない
Surely, you can't shine all by yourself either,
だからボクがずっと隣にいよう
so let me stay right by your side forever.
見てきたモノ感じたコト
All the irreplaceable things we've witnessed,
言葉にできなくても
even if we can't put them into words—
この想いを遥か彼方詩に乗せて届けよう
let's carry these feelings far away upon a song.
これから先の旅路でどんな嵐が襲ってきても
No matter what storms may come on the journey ahead,
大丈夫キミと一緒に詩を歌い続けよう
it's okay, let's keep singing songs together with you.